We're going to back to the roots a
little bit with uh MFM. Everyone says
they want more ideas. I've got two of
them.
>> Okay. Uh so, everyone's lonely. We know
this. I want to talk to you about two
different radical ideas.
>> If you're listening to this podcast, we
know.
>> You know, we know.
>> Well, these two ideas I've already been
interested in, and I was just trying to
find an excuse to tie them together. I'm
trying to make this cohesive, but
they're two great ideas and we have a
precedent of getting this first one
somewhatish right. We have predicted a
couple like biohacking things. Not
predicted, that takes too much credit,
but like we talked about it fairly early
in the adoption cycle. Would you agree?
>> We're basically big pharma.
>> We have predicted and developed several
several pharmaceutical drugs on this
podcast. Would you like to go down
memory lane of a couple of them? I don't
actually know all the ones that we did.
Obviously, GLP1, testosterone, what else
were we talking about for a long time?
>> You you've brought up GLP1s kind of
before they even got to market, before
Ozmpic ever got to market.
>> Uh TRT businesses and you were toying
around with the idea of like, hey, I
really believe there's a big business to
be built here. We didn't end up building
one, but we both invested in
>> we in well, we invested in one that that
worked. You also talked about sperm
freezing, not just egg freezing, and I
think that's also become quite a big
deal. Uh we've talked about IVF, you
know, fairly early on and the different
business opportunities that exist in
IVF. I don't think anyone's actually
done those yet. The idea there is to
build a a trusted brand in the IVF
world, a chain. Um the the Chick-fil-A
of IVF, as I like to say, and
a place you trust. Okay, but go on. What
do you got now? So, I was scrolling on
Instagram the other day and I saw two
things. One, a new version or rather
another health trend that I think is
going to be popular. And two, probably
the best way to position this new trend
I've ever seen. So, Palmer Lucky, CEO,
founder of Androl, also started Oculus.
he uh was at this conference and someone
said something to him, a question that I
tend to hate and he's one of the few
people I've ever seen to answer this
question in a great way. The question
was basically, Palmer, if you were
starting from zero and you had nothing,
no connections, what would you do? What
would you work on? And he had the best
answer.
>> If you were starting with zero today,
some bet you made wiped you out, you got
to start again. You didn't have your
network, you didn't have your wealth.
What would you do today, Palmer?
>> I would try to end the tragedy of
divorce with oxytocin doping for
marriage counseling. We understand
mammal pair bonding pretty well. There's
a lot of people who want to stay
together. Most of the people who don't
want to stay together should stay
together, especially for their kids.
Look, if if if people think SSRIs are
fine, which they're not, but if they
were, then oxytocin doping to
>> I've heard about this. It's really it's
really critical, right? So, you know,
people sort of drift apart over time.
Oxytocin is safe, but it's
>> it's understood. We use a lot of
infants.
>> It's the bonding hormone.
>> That's right. It's the mammal pair
bonding chemical. There's things you can
do to increase the uptake and there's
there it's very well understood. Also,
totally unregulated, which is great.
Unregulated spaces are a lot easier to
do. You can go buy a kilog of oxytocin
on Sigma Aldrich chemical supply right
now. And if you do that, maybe you won't
maybe you won't die alone.
>> Okay, so let's recap what we just heard
here. So Palmer Lucky, ten's a
billionaire guy, very successful. He
said, "If I had to work on something
again, it'd be saving America from the
tragedy of divorce." And that would be
oxytocin doping for marriage counseling.
If you do this, maybe you won't die
alone.
How great is that? Is that brilliant? Is
that the
>> Dude, you're absolutely right. Most of
the time when you ask somebody like,
"What would you do if you started up
again?" They'll just give you the most
vague handwavy. He immediately had not
only a great original novel, surprising
idea, but he had the pitch ready to go,
locked in.
>> The best.
>> The best. And I hate using the F-word,
first principles. I hate using that word
because it's overplayed and it's just
not used correctly. But this is like a
kind of a textbook case of that. He
starts with divorce is a huge deal. It
impacts 50% of people. What are some
potential ideas that could solve the
tragedy of divorce? You could say um a
bunch of stuff. You could say like
helping people find the right person. Uh
having good conversations early in on a
relationship. Okay, whatever. Like what
all can do this? And somehow he got to
this idea of oxytocin. And I think that
is brilliant. I'm not saying that I in
fact I am saying I know nothing about
oxytocin other than a little bit of like
nerdy research. So I'm not I'm not
saying that oxytocin is necessarily
great. What I'm saying is the packaging
of this is beautiful. And when I heard
this I realized this is actually an
interesting business idea. And I've
heard about oxytocin. The reason I've
heard about it is I follow these weird
subreddits with biohacking. And this is
how I learned about uh GLP1s. This is
how I learned about a little bit about
testosterone. And what I've noticed is
often times these people are wrong.
They'll say things that are kind of
ridiculous, but occasionally there comes
conversations where you're like, "Okay,
there's a signal here. Something is
interesting." And I followed along on
the oxytocin forum on uh on Reddit, the
subreddit, and there's there's this one
called oxy just oxytocin. And I've and
it's basically mostly autistic people.
So, a lot of people who have asberers um
a lot of people who suffer from PS uh
PTSD and they've been taking oxytocin
for a few years now because it's fairly
unregulated and I'll explain what it is
in a minute and they've like are writing
like a daily journal about how it makes
them feel and it's kind of amazing. So,
what is oxytocin? Oxytocin is a hormone
that naturally occurs in your body. The
most common way that people get oxytocin
is when women have babies. It creates a
bonding between the mother and the uh
the infant and so it right when they
have the kid it like oxytocin I believe
it's one of the is when it gets released
the mother starts creating milk and they
bond men get it after they have sex uh
you know when you're cuddling you know
that nice feeling uh that's because of
oxytocin a lot of mammals a lot of
animals the there's a strong correlation
between when you when mammals have a lot
of oxytocin they do uh bonding better
with their partners so they'll be like
they study these Um, I think it was
called prairie dogs, something like
that, and they have huge amounts of
oxytocin and they are lifelong partners
with their spouse forever,
>> right? Yeah. Like if I have a really
solid dap up with somebody, perfect hand
clap, I I feel a small surge of this
male this uh pair bonding chemical
released in my body, I can almost hear
it when it happens.
>> Or when you look your dog in the eye. So
there are studies that show when you
look at your dog and make eye contact
with your dog, you release a little bit
of oxytocin. Dude, when is it Have you
Have you recently
just had like silent eye contact very
like you're 4 inches away from your wife
and you just hold eye contact for like
30 seconds to a minute. Have you done
this?
>> No, but your friend Chris Williamson put
out this thing where it was like
questions to ask spouses to like make
you bond and like part of it was looking
at eye contact together. And I told my
wife I was like, "Hey, I want to try
this." And it's like, so we have like we
have like a scheduled time to do this.
>> I'm It's a little bit weird, but if you
want to be adventurous tonight,
>> the eye contact thing
>> is full on eye contact.
>> Do you do it?
>> Hey, I want to tell you about something
pretty cool. We have a database of all
of the business ideas that have been
discussed on this podcast. So, hundreds
of episodes the team at HubSpot went
through. They pulled out all the simple,
relatable, interesting, profitable uh
ideas that we have brainstormed. They're
all available for download for free.
Just click the link in the description
below. Thank you to our friends at
HubSpot for sponsoring this podcast and
putting together this free resource for
you guys. Back to the show.
>> Yeah, I've done this before and my wife
literally starts crying. It would make
me cry. Within 30 seconds, she starts
crying. It's like the most bizarre thing
to me cuz I don't feel the urge to cry.
I It's There's definitely an intensity
>> to it when you're just quiet and you're
looking straight into the eyes of
somebody who you know really well. Yeah,
I'm going to do it today. I'm going to
do it tonight. In fact, that's
everybody's homework tonight. 30
seconds, maybe a minute if you're
feeling freaky of straight up eye
contact.
>> Yeah. It doesn't matter if it's your
spouse or a roommate. Just the
>> or the mirror if you're really, you
know, if you're really in one of the
Spotify wrapped top 1% listeners.
>> Well, one of the reasons why you feel
that way is because of the chemical or
the hormone oxytocin. This is Isn't this
also why like skin-to-skin contact with
a baby like kind of uh you hold the baby
on your chest, they make you like take
your shirt off in the hospital
>> amongst amongst other things at you and
laugh.
>> Yeah. Yeah. That I mean I do that with
my kids. I'll be holding them and I'll
take my I pop the top. I take the shirt
off and I and I like I want to hold them
because it feels special. You bond more.
And um and what I didn't realize is that
I I I if you if you Google buy oxytocin,
you'll get like um a bunch of
interesting websites. They're usually
called like something sciences or
something pharmaceuticals where you can
buy it in like a pure I don't know if
it's pure. I'm not using these words
correctly, but from a from a idiot's
point of view, like a pure block of it.
It's a powder.
>> It's like a butter. What do you mean?
>> Like it looks like a basil spray.
>> Okay. So, here's what I'm getting at.
It's it's like a it's like a a powder,
but now
>> Yes. You can buy a ton of it. And what a
lot of companies I'm noticing they're
slowly getting into. If you go to Blue
Chew, which sells uh erectile
dysfunction medicine, if you if you go
to HIMS, I imagine they might start
selling this. But you're noticing is
that this fringe thing is be being
turned into a nasal spray because that's
the only way that you could take it. You
can either take it through that or I
think like a like a gas mask. You can't
inject it. It's not a pill, but they're
starting to sell this. And my
prediction,
>> you do you do need a prescription for
it. It looks like
>> not to buy it on some of these websites.
Like you can just you can click and
order it right now.
>> Yes. So you you you sent this over and
this immediately
got my bra like I feel like my brain
overheated for a minute because when you
hear a genuinely interesting great idea
that that you don't understand fully.
You don't know you haven't researched
it. You don't know the the efficacy of
it. You don't know the safety of it. So
that that those are all the caveats.
>> Yeah of an idea. It could still be
like right like this is totally
underststudied. So let's preface
everything by saying that. Well, we
should explain the prairie prairie vole
thing uh the study that they did. So,
most animals are not monogamous, right?
But there are a few that are that have
an intense, you know, bond, a monogamy.
And so they've studied these prairie vos
where once the male and female mate and
they bond and they spend enough of this
like brief time together, they will be
monogous for life and they will not only
not go with other partners, they'll even
attack if another like if a male is
there and a female comes, he will like
kind of push her away. And then they did
studies on this in a very small sample
size. So, not like a robust study, like
a maybe study where they did
this with humans and they had a placebo
and they had humans that would take
oxytocin and they would see what would
happen. And you know, for example, in
one of them, they would have an
attractive female come in and if the
person had had the oxytocin bonding with
their partner, they would sit like an
extra 15 cm apart from the attractive
female, they would create distance uh
between them and the attractive female
or they would spend less time looking at
them, things like that. Now again, small
studies, but it's very interesting that
most people, we like to think that we're
in control of our mind, that we're in
control of how we how we're going to
feel and how we're going to act. And so,
I'd say there's one one group of people
that think they can think their way to a
behavior. There's another group of
people that would be feelings-based, and
they say, "Well, it's not about logic
and and thinking your way there. It's a
feeling thing." But feelings to them are
this amorphous sort of you know mystical
thing. It's just something that happens
about like the idea of a soul. Whereas
in truth, the
feel basically a feeling is a chemical
brain state that you're in and then you
have a conscious readout of it that
says, "Oh, I really like the way that
that mean that means I'm in love, right?
This brain state, this the way I feel
when I'm doing this or when I'm with
this person, that means I love this.
That means I hate this. That means I'm
disgusted by this." Right? So, we have a
a kind of a readout of the chemical
state. And if we could find safe ways
to
alter or or or grease the wheels on
certain uh chemical states, that's
really interesting to me. And the reason
why is the all these ideas sound a
little far-fetched before we had the
miracle weight loss drugs, right? Like
there used to literally be a phrase that
was like uh there's no magic pill for
weight loss, but now there is. There's
literally a magic pill for weight loss.
Well, what if there's a magic pill for
for love or for being um bonded with
your partner? I find that really really
interesting. And then I think further
the example you just gave of people who
are autistic or have asberers using this
to bridge maybe a social gap that they
have um is really interesting. And when
I was reading about this just before the
podcast, you mentioned this idea and I
had never heard of it. One of the ways
that it was described was it's like a
highlighter. So, it's not that like it's
not a love potion. It's not like you
take something and you immediately fall
in love with the first person you see or
anything like that. What it does is it
highlights or um amplifies what you
feel. So, they they did studies where if
somebody was domestically abused, they
wouldn't this wouldn't like override
that and make them feel love towards the
person. It would heighten their sense of
uh distance between that person. So, it
was taking whatever the social feeling
you have underneath and just amplifying
it. So if it was bad, it would amplify
that you want to get away from that
person. And if it was good, the warmth,
it would amplify the warmth for that
person. So I find that really I find
that that angle of it to be really
promising cuz that would be
life-changing for people who have
trouble connecting socially and in
relationships, right?
>> Yeah. It's pretty magical. Um well, the
idea is magical. And uh I was listening
to someone else uh some other doctor
talk about it and he was basically
saying he was like look like there's not
like that much data to back this up. So
it's not necessarily that it's disproven
but it's also not proven yet. But he was
like we've been doing some small stuff
where we would give it to like small
teams. And he didn't explain what a team
was but it could have been like
co-workers or even a sports team
whatever people working together. and he
was like, "They worked together so much
better when they all had small doses of
oxytocin." And I found that to be really
fascinating. And I like ideas that seem
very freakish and strange. Like imagine
walking into your office or going to a
team retreat, which I just had, and
everyone has to do oxytocin in advance.
That's very weird, right? That's
off-putting. That's strange.
>> Yes.
>> But like maybe maybe that's kind of
interesting. And so I went and texted
>> Adam Newman somewhere is like yes not
weird we are doing that
>> but I just I I think it's interesting. I
I think this is really interesting and I
tweeted this out. I'm like who has done
this? And someone was like, "Don't do
stuff that you read on forums." And I'm
like, "Yeah, don't do it because we are
talking about it or because someone else
is talking about it." But there's some
interesting signal there, particularly
from a marketing standpoint, but
potentially for like a a selfish
standpoint of like maybe maybe there is
something here cuz I've seen this enough
times that when people that we call
strange where they're doing something,
there's something there. And there's
this subreddit where these guys There's
one guy who had Asberers and he was
talking about I keep calling it
Asberers. Is it Asberers? Am I saying it
wrong? Sorry guys. I think
>> there's a P in there somewhere between
burger that you're saying.
>> It's not ask per. Uh, sorry guys. The
subreddit where these guys who have this
are talking about like they're writing
daily journals and they're like, "All
right, I just took the dose. Okay, I'm
feeling hoardy now. That's probably too
much of a dose. Okay, 10 hours later, I
took a second dose. I noticed that I
it's I struggled to make eye contact
with my children most of the time. Now,
it was way easier to make eye contact
and I had a significantly better
conversation. Like, they're documenting
this and it's so interesting to me. I
would not be surprised if in 12 months
you and me and our listener are going to
get a lot of meta ads saying this will
cure divorce or something like that.
>> Well, I'm the type that I have an
initial reaction to these things. Like,
I don't I don't do drugs. I I don't even
go to Burning Man because I'm scared of
like, you know, just new new experience.
I'm very happy in my life and it's kind
of like to chill uh in a in a happy
little bubble. I I always have an a a
kind of fear-based reaction to things
that sound weird, unfamiliar, or like,
you know, chemically altering. And I
think there's some good there's
definitely some good in that, right?
There's there's obviously you can
protect yourself that way. But it's also
o over time I've seen how things that
initially sounded very fringe can become
very normal in not that long of a time.
You know, like um when you years ago
were like, "Oh, I hurt my Achilles and
so I injected BPC whatever 157 in my and
it's and it's healing my Achilles." And
I'm like, "That's a crazy thing to do."
You're like, "No, it's the Wolverine
stack or whatever." Right? Like I'm
like, "Yeah, even more reason not to
take this." You know, turn turns you
into a Wolverine or whatever. Like I I
don't know. I don't want that. Um and
now peptides are are are shockingly
common. And uh same thing recently a uh
psychedelics company just got acquired
for $3 billion by Eli Liy. Did you see
this?
>> No. What was it called?
>> It's probably the biggest um psychedelic
acquisition ever. This company called I
don't know how you say it. Atea Beckley.
They just got bought for 2.8 billion.
And you know psychedelics are the same
sort of thing, right? Like you know
growing up psychedelics were seen as a
certain way, right? It's like you know
tripping balls and uh it's a it's a way
to have a good time. And then and now
psychedelics is I would say amongst
smart friends considered to be one of
the best interventions for people who
have PTSD and other forms of deep trauma
as a way to kind of do 20 years of
therapy in 20 minutes type of Now
again this is maybe anecdotal whatever.
All I know is it went from very fringe
and and labeled a certain way to way
more mainstream and now seen in a very
different light. But it's the same
thing. this the sort of um social
acceptance shifts over time for these
things and I suspect
that something like this is also
something that where social acceptance
could shift over time. The idea you said
of, hey, before we go to this team
retreat, uh, you know, quick, everyone
puff, you know, let's let's do the flown
in our nose here real quick. It's going
to help. That sounds like laughable
right now, but I don't know. I I've seen
this shift over time many times now,
right? So, who's to say this isn't also
one where where that might might be
true?
>> I have I texted Jack Smith, our resident
uh biohacker, and I said, um, have you
ever taken this? and he said, "No, but
one time an intern at my company got
effed up on it after uh he took some.
And then once I took a taxi driver and I
was telling the taxi driver about it and
he asked to be paid in it
that
so uh the the opportunity sniffing blood
hounds, something's there." So that's
cool. U that that was one of mine. Um
but I think that's interesting. And so
this is this is one of those things
where we're going to have to look back
in 12 months and be like, were we were
we on that or not?
>> 10 out of 10. Great segment.
>> Um, okay. Second one. Have you ever
heard of the Knights of Columbus?
>> No. Is this that medieval play that you
told me about once?
>> No, that's
>> where you go. It's like a buffet. What
is that called?
>> No, that's a Renaissance fair. I forget
the name of the restaurant, but So,
check this out. So, we're talking about
the lon loneliness epidemic a little
bit. Uh, so in 1882, there was this guy.
He was a priest up in New Haven in
Connecticut. What was his name? His name
was uh McGiving. He was a Catholic
priest. Someone in his parish died. And
he was like, "Dude, this sucks. This man
had two kids and a wife and he died. He
was the earner for his family. We have
to do something about this." So he
convinced something like 200 of his male
people in his priest to join what he
called a mutual benefit society where
they would all chip in money and they
would help pay for this guy's family for
a little while and then if any any of
them other uh died some of the money
would go towards them. This sounds very
similar to life insurance, right? Um and
that's sort of what it became. And so
the Knights of Columbus is now an
organization. It's a fraternal
organization that's been around since
1882. It has something like 2 or three
million members. They have $30 billion
in assets. They do like 10 or5 or 10
billion a year in revenue. And it's a
fraternal organization for Catholic men.
And the whole thing is that they um you
pay dues something like $300 a year and
you basically show up in your church
after hours and you guys plan charities
that you're going to do together. So
predominantly it's like pancake drives
or they do a lot of like homeless stuff
and they're there to help each other and
at this point they're a huge lobby. They
like it's quite powerful. But the way
that they make money is they sell life
insurance to their members and they
crush it. It's been around for over a
hundred years and it's a massive
business. And I've always been
interested in this type of business. And
what this is is basically a shared
interest group that they get together
for and and help other people or help
themselves in a variety of ways. And it
monetizes by selling financial products,
insurance products. And I think that
this is a really interesting business
for a couple reasons. Number one, the
Knights of Columbus, they are actually
growing mostly through young men. For
decades, young men were not joining. It
was mostly old men. Um, and they have
local chapters. I think they have like
14,000 chapters all over the country and
it was mostly old men and it was kind of
dying and what they're noticing is that
young men uh like between 30 and 40 are
joining and it's their fastest growing
segment.
>> So I'm interested in it for that reason.
The second reason I'm interested in it
is because these exist for all types of
organizations. So for example uh let's
use GoodSam as an example. Have you
heard of Goods Sam?
>> No. What is GoodSam? Good Sam is an RV
owner membership. So, it's all based
around a shared identity and community
and they monetize through financial
stuff. So, Good Sam is if you own an RV,
you spend a couple hundred a year and
you get some better insurance for your
RV, but you also get like you get
discounts to like campgrounds and things
like that.
>> Okay.
>> Um, another one is there's this thing
for uh it's called the USCCCA. I was a
member of it. When you get your conceal
and carry license, you can pay $300 and
you can get access to monthly trainings
for like gun ownership, but also you get
insurance if you ever get prosecuted for
shooting someone. And they do about $400
million a year in revenue. And these are
huge businesses that last a very long
time. And in my opinion, there's a lot
of interesting opportunities to jump on
this whole loneliness thing and monetize
it via financial products. You're saying
you basically take a deep interestbased
community. Yeah.
>> Could be religious, could be
non-religious, could be RV owners or
whatever. Um, and then you become a
member. You get to meet other members.
So, you kind of get community belonging.
You get maybe some discounts that
immediately kind of justify the value of
your your membership because it's
marketing for them. But the real the
real banana is you figure out how to
sell a finan a commodity financial
service but people will have some
preferential attachment to you because
you are the community
>> 100%. And I think now is an interesting
time because the loneliness thing it's
quite easy to like capitalize on that.
And two these things last forever. What
do you think?
>> Well I I mean I've never heard of this.
I have heard of healthc care shares. I
mean, I guess in general that's a thing,
right? Like there's a whole health
insurance, life insurance model that's
kind of like this is usually religious,
I think, is the the general way these
go. And I never understood if this is
just some tax loophole type stuff or if
there's a better value prop for these
things. Do you do you know a lot about
these healthcare share programs? For
some, it depends what your offering is.
For some of them, there is tax benefits.
So, there's some like weird rules around
if you are a membership and you are
considered a um I think they call it a
me um uh a mutual benefit membership
where like everyone gets the same
benefits. You do get where you don't
have to pay taxes on I think it's the
the g the investment gains of your
premium something like that. There is
some tax advantages for sure, but that's
not required in order to make this
awesome.
>> So, so I'm looking at this now. So, so
it looks like these healthcare share
programs are often like instead of
paying into your paying, you know, two
grand a month to Blue Cross, you pay the
same two grand a month or maybe even a
little bit less, you pay maybe a
thousand a month into a healthcare share
program. And now if anybody in the
community has that $40,000 surgical
bill, the group coordinates to get the
money paid out to that person who needs
it. But I think there's some weird stuff
where like legally they're not obligated
to pay it. It's like a high trust type
of situation, but like not contractual
in the same way that that health
insurance might be. Although people who
have had trouble getting health
insurance to pay for things that they
think should be covered probably would
disagree that that that is any more
likely to be paid out is is is probably
a fair fair criticism.
>> But what's going on here? First of all,
health insurance is like a whole another
thing where I'm like I I don't know if I
would touch that. That's very messy. But
the majority of these businesses, they
are not insurance companies. they are
partners with someone else who does it
and they get uh a more tailored plan.
>> So, so the Knights of Columbus, they
just have all the money in the members
and then they go to who?
>> Uh, Knights of Columbus might be one of
the few that does it because they're big
enough, but like AAP, if you know AP, so
AP does billions of dollars a year in
revenue. AP is uh association of retired
people. I think it's if you're above 50
or 60, you automatically get a letter
from AP that says, "Hey, come join AP.
You'll get our magazine. You can come to
some of our events and you'll get uh a
discount on your health insurance." And
they partner with United and so they are
not they license their name. So, they
are the trusted brand and so and like
the marketing channel, but they do not
actually provide the health insurance,
but but they're a partner and so they
aren't actually running that.
>> Well, these these faith-based businesses
are very interesting. So, um, I just did
a a a interview with the guy behind
Angel Studios. So, Angel is probably the
10th biggest studio in the world and
you've never heard of it. And it's
basically all values-based content they
call it, which is like one out of every
10 of their movies or TV shows is
religious. like it'll be like um the
Jesus like Game of Thrones for but the
but the book underlying book is the New
Testament and it's like called the
chosen are chosen something like that.
It's like a a show about Jesus and he
said 200 million people have watched
that show.
>> What?
>> Um it's like it's like on Amazon Prime.
It's like one of the one of the most
watched shows ever in the history of
television is that show. It's on se it's
on the seventh season and they help
produce the first three seasons of that.
But they make they make all kinds of
movies and shows and their community is
basically 3 million members who want
content that's going to have no cursing,
no drinking, no drugs, um stuff like
that. And also just heroes, like good
good people doing good things are in the
movie. So like it can't be just like a
dark film where like everybody's kind of
bad, right? Or like everybody's flawed
and messed up and it's just a bunch of
messed up people living together, right?
like they're trying to avoid that type
of content. And so like for example,
they have one movie right now called The
Runner. If you watch the trailer for it,
it's Owen Wilson and um this guy Allen,
whatever, Richardson, something like
that. And basically the the premise of
the thing is they're delivering a an
organ donor, like they're organ donor uh
van. They're like driving this this
liver and suddenly like three cars like
pull up in front of it and they have
guns and they're like, "Um, how much
does this liver go for on the black
market?" They're like a million dollars
and they're like, "Oh we got to
get out of here." And
>> I saw that trailer last night in a movie
and in my head I was thinking there's
like 18 guys like trying to kidnap this
this body part for only a million
dollars.
It's crazy. Like they did so much work
for I I
>> What kind of margins is this is this
operation running?
>> I just that doesn't that doesn't seem
worth it, right? Like in the movie
they're like blowing stuff up. You see
the cost of ammunition lately?
>> They definitely spent more than a
million to to get Yeah, I saw that
>> to get delivered.
>> But the um and so what about it?
>> Well, the the So, but this this business
is a juggernaut. They're doing 400 plus
million dollars a year in ARR.
>> What?
>> 450 million in ARR. It's a public
company. You can see their their their
data. And the way they did it was they
basically said they had a worldview. In
fact, the guy who started it, he's this
epic marketer who did um the marketing
behind like PooPourri and Squatty Potty.
He was like one of these like really
viral marketers, you know, like Dollar
Shave Club. Like they would make videos
like that.
>> Dude, there's like a whole like Mormon
cabal of these like really good
marketers up there in Salt Lake and they
they all those companies I think you
named are either Mormon based or like
some affiliation and they're really good
at marketing. So this guy's a Latter Day
Saint and and you know, so what he did
was he was like tired of looking at like
YouTube videos where you know your kids
you never know what you're going to get
when your kids click on YouTube like
they can get to they're two clicks away
from watching somebody like you know
smoke meth. And so he's like you know
that's not great. So he created this
like filter and because the project
didn't even start as a real business. He
literally just took a movie. I think it
was like Cinderella Man. It it it he it
would wipe out all of the cursing, the
sex scenes, the drug scenes, but it
would leave the the rest of the movie.
And so he's like, you know, the
gluten-free movie basically. Yeah.
>> And so he creates this filter and he
publishes it. Uh he publishes the movie
and immediately gets sued and he ends up
having to like pay $10 million in a
lawsuit somewhere along the way. But he
this tool and these movies started
attracting
um a lot of people. So like a 100,000
people eventually wanted like the
service. They then started doing this
thing where like you would go rent like
technically you would rent the DVD for a
dollar and then that gave the his group
the like permission to like wipe out all
the scenes and then give it back give
you the streaming version of it or
something like that. created this whole
loophole to try to make this business
work and finally said, "All right, I'm
tired of getting like sued by the by the
movie industry because they don't like
that we're doing this. Why don't we just
make our own movies and our own TV shows
that just have like out of the box are
clean, you know, better for you?"
>> Did he raise funding?
>> Um, yeah, they raised some money. Um,
but like it's amazing that they've, you
know, they've reached this incredible
scale and it's really only like, you
know, they it's like two or three
million people. It's not like that many
people, but two or three million people
each who pay, you know, 13 to 20 bucks a
month for this subscript this streaming
service, you know, just like you're
paying for Peacock and Paramount and,
you know, whatever tier 2, tier three
streamer service that you you you
subscribe to. Um, and then the members
vote on the content. So, basically,
they'll take a uh a movie that's already
made and they'll show the the trailer or
they'll show like a snippet of the movie
to the 2 million members and the members
vote. And if 70% if less than 70% green
light it, the deal is dead no matter
what. But if more than 70% say yes, then
the movie like kind of uh gets picked up
by them and it's going to go into their
marketing pipeline and whatnot. And they
have like a higher average like Rotten
Tomatoes and hit rate than you know all
the popular studios.
>> How did you meet this guy? Ben met him
somewhere at a barbecue or something
like that and was you know Ben knows
that I've been um you know curious about
the movie and TV industry and making a
movie and he said you know you should
talk to this guy he's done it you know
he's went from no experience in the
movie business to now doing almost half
a billion dollars a year in revenue for
their movie kind of kind of their like
values-based A24 right like
>> do you know anything I I saw a movie
last night I went and saw the Chris
Hansen movie you know what that is
>> catch a predator Yeah, he got a movie.
>> It's about him that he doesn't like.
>> Didn't he get cancelled also or
something though? What?
>> I think he was cheating on his wife. I
don't think he was a predator, but I
don't think he was breaking the law, but
I think he was doing not good stuff.
That's that's part of the movie is that
he was uh while he was doing this, he
wasn't like the a good husband
basically. And it's called Prime Time.
It was pretty great. Um and it's got
Robert Patterson. It was awesome. It's
an A24 movie. in every great trailer
leading up to the movie uh was 824. I
don't really know anything about 824
other than Scott Bellski um who who I
have a man crush on was a tech guy is
now working there. Do you know anything
about 824?
>> Well, what do you want to know? I know
some things about 824, but I'm not an
expert.
>> How on how does someone start a studio?
Like because it seems like they came out
of nowhere. It seemed like there was a
startup at first and if I remember
correctly, their movies early on were
kind of kind of dumb or artsy. like they
weren't like mainstream movies, but now
it seems like everything they do, I want
to see it.
>> Well, one of my business theories is
that uh a great way to think of a
business uh idea is to find the reaction
to the action. Like for example, when
Facebook was in its absolute prime and
everyone was using Facebook, Facebook
created this world where all your photos
would be public and they would be
permanent. You'd post them on your
profile, your timeline, your history,
everyone could see them. And so that
became the action and the reaction
became Snapchat photos you could send
that would self-destruct in 10 seconds.
And it's actually that the the
popularity of one creates the need for
the other. And you see this a lot of
times, right? So you as you know, we
talked about GLP1s. As food calories
become abundant, you know, you have Door
Dash and you have fast food and you have
all these, you know, the way that the
food industry went, well then there
became a higher a greater need for the
reaction. And this happens over and over
and over again. You see this right now
with like screen time limiting apps and
brick and things like that. like things
that are getting quite popular that are
really just like a reaction to kind of
the the current norm. And so, uh, A24
was also a reaction to the action in a
way where the movie studios and the
people in Hollywood really started to
become extremely conservative and
predictable in the movies that they
would film uh, fund cuz why would you
fund an unproven screenplay by this, you
know, cool hipster who's drinking matcha
when you could just go do Spider-Man 7,
you know, like why why not? Why not just
do Spider-Man again? And so they kept
gravitating towards what they call these
like four quadrant movies. I don't know
if you've seen like the quadrants. Have
Have you ever heard this before? What
are they?
>> It's like males under 30, females under
30, males over 30, females over 30 is
whatever a simplified version of that,
but it's basically the big short. Like
if if both of us said like, yo, do you
like the big shorts? I love the big
short. Well, we love the big short cuz
we're in one of those quadrants and it
hits for us, but guess who it doesn't
hit for? It doesn't hit for like women
over 40 in the same way as it does for,
you know, men in their kind of 20 to
40s. And so the highest kind of
potential for a film is something that
satisfies all four quadrants. You know,
Harry Potter right now is like if you
go, you know, the new HBO uh series for
Harry Potter, they'll put a billion
dollars into this because they know that
millennials who read it growing up are
now 30, 40, 50, you know, 50 years old.
They like it, but so do kids still. And
so you're going to get this a huge
demographic. The TAM is really large.
And so what happened was studios became
quite riskaverse and they started
gravitating towards sequels, superhero
films, and other things. A that created
an opportunity for folks like A24 who
could go pick up at pretty low cost and
pretty uncompetitively
all the other films that were being
ignored. All what are the great films
that are being ignored right now? And so
what they found was that these
independent directors were
creating really interesting things that
could be produced on a fairly low
budget, had pretty low expectations cuz
they there was not a lot of demand in
Hollywood for their their product. And
so they started creating cool, edgy,
they're making stuff nobody else was
making. So they were like differentiated
out of the box.
>> Do you remember the the early movies? It
looks like um like it was like the movie
The Room, which I saw. It was pretty
awesome. Um, I don't know some of the
other earlier ones. So, do you?
>> Um, no. And I'm sure, by the way, this
is like a extreme oversimplification and
somebody who like lives in the movie
business is probably like yelling at
their phone right now being like, "What?
That's not it. That's not the whole
story. You're forgetting A, B, and C."
And I'm sure there's A, B, and C. And
they did a bunch of things. Well, you
know, they they branded their studio.
Well, they have limited edition merch.
They figured out a different form of
marketing. So like the Timothy Shalamé
like uh where he leaked his you know the
movie trailer instead of saying this
this summer coming to a movie theater
near you. This guy this guy in the
pottest film of the year it was like a
Zoom recording like a meeting that got
accidentally leaked that had a file name
that sounded like a real thing and it
was like an hour long and it was this
weird thing that they were doing. um you
know that that sort of stuff. You know,
for example, the guy yesterday was
saying they have a movie with Kevin
James, you know, like King of Queens,
Kevin Kevin James, and they were like,
he was like to market that movie, uh,
Kevin James was like, "Hey, you know,
the character in this, he's like this
painter, this like teacher who's like a
painter, so let's just create an
Instagram account where I'm a teacher
and a painter. We don't even mention."
And people are going to be like, "Isn't
that Kevin James?" But then people will
be like, "Is that just like a Kevin
James lookalike? This guy says he lives
here and he's just painting every day
and he doesn't What? What's going on?
Let's just do weird like that. And
then they sent him to the Super Bowl and
they bought 12 seats and they left, you
know, 10 of them empty. And he sat, you
know, 11 of them empty. He sat in the
middle of the Super Bowl with with empty
seats on either side. He was wearing a
tuxedo and he's holding flowers cuz
that's like a famous scene from the
movie. And they didn't even explain what
was going on. And suddenly, and then but
they paid for other influencers to be in
the same section cuz they knew those
influencers would be like, "Dude, that's
Kevin James and why are all those empty
seats? Why is he wearing a tuxedo? And
why is he holding flowers?" They put out
their story and it created intrigue and
people started wondering what the hell's
going on and then the movie comes out
and it does really well because they can
like do this gorilla marketing that the
traditional studios don't really
understand or don't have the like DNA to
go do. I think A24 and some of the
upstarts have figured out that because
making like when you think about the
cost of making a movie it's pretty
mind-blowing. So he was talking about a
movie they made. He goes yeah it cost 14
million to make. Okay. How much you
spend on marketing? 40. So 14 million to
make and 40 on marketing.
>> Whoa. So the 14 million, does that
include the actor's salary?
>> Everything. Yeah. Full production cost.
>> So it's $54 million all in for this.
>> All in. So So but but this is very
common. I was talking to a friend who
made a movie and I was like it had been
three or four years since he had first
told me about the idea to when it came
out and I was like damn that's takes
forever but I guess that's just the
creative process. And he's like do you
know how long filming takes for a movie?
I was like no. He goes, "30 days." 37
days for us. I was like, "You shot the
whole thing in 37 days?" He goes, "Yep."
End to end 37 days. And that's complet.
I was like, "Was that fast?" He goes,
"No, that's normal. 30 days. That's how
long it normally takes to shoot these
things."
>> Is that the editing takes a long time
postprouction?
>> What's that?
>> A normal movie can only take 30 or 60 or
90 days.
>> The the actual shooting of the the
filming of the movie.
>> Wow.
>> So, you you spend time like writing,
getting it funded. That could take like
years sometimes to get it like to get it
to the for day one of principal
production and then afterwards you have
to do all the other like mixing,
mastering, color correction, like all
that stuff that can take time. The edit
can take a lot of time and then you have
the marketing and distribution. So the
whole thing takes years but the the
making of the movie like the the actual
like hey lights camera action go say
your lines that thing's like 30 days
which is insane to me. Same thing with
cost. Like uh I think the Grand Theft
Auto games,
>> they would spend like a couple hundred
million making the game, like years of
development and engineering time and
animation and all that stuff, but then
they would spend equally like hundreds
of millions on marketing. Uh and like uh
maybe not Grand Theft Auto specifically,
but video game for the video game
industry is very common to do that. So
for movies and and video games, which
are two of the kind of like biggest, you
know, parts of the American economy,
they spend more money on marketing than
they do on actually making the product,
which is Some people would say it's kind
of sad, but it's kind of crazy.
>> This business is foreign to me. Um I
definitely we should do a whole episode
on like
>> seems like a terrible business. He was
telling me he was our biggest hit. It
did 250 million box office. Um and but
it only cost us 14 to make. So then I
go, okay, how much was the other cost
like marketing? So that's 40. Okay, so
now we're at now we're at 54 250 million
in revenue. All right, that's not bad.
You got a 5x return. Oh, but wait,
that's the box office. So, how much do
you keep out of that? Like, what does
the theater get the distributor? He's
like, "Well, 50%." Because we're big
much smaller than that if uh if you're
kind of a new newcomer. So, the 250
becomes 125.
125 on against 54 million to create. So,
you you your biggest hit in like a hits
driven business where you're going to
have lots of flops.
>> Yeah. That profit needs to cover six
flops
>> is is like a 2 somethingx return.
But that's the same way with all with
with all creative businesses, that's the
case. So, for example, um Mark Manson
when he came on two or three years ago,
he either said this on the podcast or
when I was hanging out with him, his
book for I think it was Penguin sold 20
million copies. Um, and he was telling
me one time, uh, he was like, "Yeah,
like my mom and dad, like they always
kind of gave me a hard time because I
was they thought I was just kind of
playing on the computer because I was
blogging and then I it turned into a
book deal and all this stuff." And I was
like, "Well, when did they start taking
you seriously?" He was like, "Well,
Penguin put out their annual I think it
was Penguin, I could be getting it
wrong, but they put out their annual
report because they're owned by News
Corp." And he was like, "They said that
I outsold Hillary Clinton and I was uh
and I helped like make the whole company
profitable that year. Uh and he like was
and I was like wait so you were the
reason the company was profitable and
basically with a lot of these publishing
businesses whether it's games or it's
movies it's like one or two things it's
drives everything and the rest is like
hopefully it doesn't fail.
>> That's normal. What was surprising to me
was that the one or two things that hit
really big like your biggest hit I would
have just expected to be much more than
like a 2 and 1/2x return. I would have
thought it's like a like in his case
like a book. Yes, you're right. Most
books fail, sure, but when a book hits,
like the subtle art hit, and you sell
10, 20 million copies, well, that book
costs almost nothing to print. And so,
they're printing money when it hits. And
um that's what I was surprised at. You
know, like in startup investing, like
you get a 50x, 100x, a 200x, a 1000x
return when you hit. And I was surprised
that the movie business isn't like that.
Uh or at least my layman's understanding
from a few of his a few of his examples
and looking at their business.
>> Yeah. and it doesn't seem like it's a
fun business to be in right now.
>> And I think he explained why, by the
way. He goes, "Have you ever met a
billionaire who doesn't want to make a
movie?" I haven't. And he said like
there are every year, let's say a
thousand films get made, far less than
that get distributed. So most even of
the films that get made, not just the
films that get pitched and and written
like screenplays and stuff.
>> I think there's some uh tax advantages
there. I get pitched this all the time
and I never like I get these emails and
I never like actually seriously read
them but isn't there something where if
you fund a movie there's some type of
like you can depreciate something weird
>> but it's uh it's not that good like uh
you can it's a you can write it off but
it has to be has the thing has to go
into production. So it's not like you
could just like say you're doing it and
like get it. You have to actually spend
the money. the money has to go into the
project and the project has to actually
go get start, you know, day one of
production. They changed the rules on
this and so it has to actually get get
made and if there's no return, well,
yeah, you might have saved money in
taxes, but you lost your entire
principle. You know what I mean? Like if
you put a million dollars in, maybe you
get a 300k writeoff, but you might lose
your million dollars. You'll probably
lose your million dollars. I didn't
think it was going to take the entire
episode to give a shout out to Grinder,
by the way. What? They listened to the
So, we had the
>> Oh, are you wearing a Are you wearing a
Grinder vest,
>> dude? They listened to the episode uh
that we had with the uh F or the the
former owners of Grinder. Great episode.
Did not hit in terms of YouTube.
Wonderful episode with M Rick Marini
when we talked about Grinder and how
they like turned the business around.
They decided to send me some merch and
it's kind of the least gay merch ever.
It's it's an arcteric vest. Like I
wanted something a little bit more like
with some pizzazz,
>> like a scarf.
>> Yeah, I don't know. Like something like
this is this is way too straight for me.
I wanted something a little bit more
gay. I thought it would be more
enjoyable.
But I appreciate the love, Grinder. I
just wish that uh you'd lean in a little
bit.
>> Grinder, where's my puffy vest? This is
a hot collab. Grinder MFM.
>> Well, that's it. That's the pod.